<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Wabisebi</title><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Blogging experiment. Japanese culture, language learning, coding and other things I'm into.</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 21:13:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 21:13:50 +0100</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
2001 Blogging Odyssey
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The rest of the text file is a <strong>Markdown</strong> blog post. The process will continue
as soon as you exit your editor.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_life.html'>life</a>, <a href='tag_code.html'>code</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/2001-blogging-odyssey.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./2001-blogging-odyssey.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 21:13:47 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Blogging like it&rsquo;s 2001
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>In 2001, I learned to code my first website—a site all about Spider-Man comics, something I was into collecting at the time. It was built in HTML, using iframes and everything. Then came a Harry Potter fan site with a custom cursor in the shape of a wand, followed a year later by a website celebrating the then newly launched Xbox. These were somewhat early days of the internet, and I just registered xbox.net. I received an email from Microsoft at the time, giving me access to the latest news about Xbox, hoping my site would grow. They didn&rsquo;t realize I was only twelve at the time.</p>

<p>All these website projects were abandoned as quickly as they were conceived. Once the novelty wore off, I jumped to the next thing. This pattern would follow me for many years to come.</p>

<p>Two years ago, I started working on a website called Wabisebi. It started out as a simple idea to blog about my interest in Japan&hellip;</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_life.html'>life</a>, <a href='tag_code.html'>code</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/title-on-this-line.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./title-on-this-line.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 19:47:42 +0100</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
