<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Wabisebi</title><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Blogging experiment. Japanese culture, language learning, coding and other things I'm into.</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 17:28:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 17:28:10 +0100</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
It Doesn&rsquo;t Count if You Don&rsquo;t Share it
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>In my previous post, I talked about my bad habit of not finishing self-initiated projects. A frustrating side-effect of this is that I will inevitably see another person executing a very similar idea, sharing it publicly and receiving positive feedback. These are usually illustrations or art projects which are very close to something I have been working on for a long time but never felt like it was ready to share.</p>

<p>I recently came across two passages that have helped me realize that I have only myself to blame for feeling upset when this happens.</p>

<p>In his book <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60965426-the-creative-act">The Creative Act: A Way of Being</a>, music producer Rick Rubin shares what I find to be a beautiful perspective on <em>ideas</em>. I think of his view as seeing ideas almost like independent entities floating in the universe, waiting to be found and brought to life.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;If you have an idea you&rsquo;re excited about and you don&rsquo;t bring it to life, it&rsquo;s not uncommon for the idea to find its voice through another maker. This isn&rsquo;t because the other artist stole your idea, but because the idea&rsquo;s time has come.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Author and marketer <a href="https://seths.blog/">Seth Godin</a> states it less poetically in his book <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53479927-the-practice?from_search=true&amp;from_srp=true&amp;qid=KNybrLUG3u&amp;rank=1">The Practice: Shipping Creative Work</a> and cuts straight to the point when explaining the importance of <em>shipping</em> your idea or product out into the world.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Shipping, because it doesn&rsquo;t count if you don&rsquo;t share it.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Of course that&rsquo;s not to say that we can&rsquo;t make things purely for ourselves, which definitely counts in its own way. But if we want feedback and a relationship with others through our work, it will only happen if we actually put it out there.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve decided to try and share things in a state where they might not yet feel &lsquo;perfect&rsquo; (whatever that means), rather than waiting too long and losing interest or missing the moment. It might not ever be a masterpiece, but at least it now counts.
<img src="./img/godin-rubin-books.webp" alt="Seth Godin and Rick Rubin Books" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_thoughts.html'>thoughts</a></p>






<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/sharing-counts.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./sharing-counts.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 18:01:29 +0100</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Clean Slate
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>In 2001, I coded my first website, all about Spider-Man comics. I built it in HTML, complete with iframes and speech bubble drawings for the navigation. More sites followed: a Harry Potter fan site and a site celebrating the newly-launched Xbox to name a few.</p>

<p>Each project was abandoned as quickly as it was conceived. Once the novelty wore off, I&rsquo;d jump to the next thing, leaving behind a wasteland of iframes and half-written introductions.</p>

<p>This pattern of jumping from project to project has followed me throughout my life.</p>

<p>Two years ago, I started working on <em>Wabisebi</em>, a blog about Japan. Soon came additional ideas: book reviews, artist spotlights, and a language study section. I hired developers, kept adding features, and talked up this great project I was building. But like always, the novelty wore off and perfectionism kicked in. The thought of filling and illustrating the entire blog became overwhelming.</p>

<p>Recently I spent a lot of time reflecting on this recurring problem and decided to try out a change. Sometimes it&rsquo;s good to do the <em>reverse</em> of what has not been working.</p>

<p>So, instead of building a website with tons of features that I then need to fill up, I&rsquo;ve decided to start bottom-up. Starting at its most basic fundamentals and only implementing things when they are <em>really</em> needed. I&rsquo;m using this simple <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">bashlog script</a>, which converts markdown text into HTML pages and let&rsquo;s me post straight from the command line. Sometimes the best way forward is to strip everything back to its essentials and just begin.</p>

<p><img src="./img/pico-markdown.png" alt="cleanslate" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_life.html'>life</a>, <a href='tag_code.html'>code</a></p>








<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/clean-slate.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./clean-slate.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 12:41:52 +0100</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
