<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title></title><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description></description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:43:37 +0900</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:43:37 +0900</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Forgotten item
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>忘れ物</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>





<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/forgotten-item.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./forgotten-item.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:21:30 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Sentence Mining Spam Messages
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A few days ago, I signed up for the JRE Card, which is a point card linked to my Suica travel card. Basically, I can earn points at most shops around the station by purchasing things like coffee. These points can then be used for travel discounts. I hastily set up the app and accidentally gave it permission to send all types of notifications—resulting in a constant stream of spam. However, rather than getting annoyed by it, I turned it into a little game: as soon as I fully understand the spam message, I allow myself to turn it off.</p>

<p><img src="./img/2025_07_10_jre.jpg" alt="JRE_Spam" />
This spam message is perfect for sentence mining—it contains only one (compound) word I didn’t know yet: 新着情報.</p>

<p><img src="./img/2025_07_10_lookup.jpg" alt="JRE_Spam" /><em>I use the app Shirabe Jisho on my iPhone to quickly look up words—either by taking a photo of the text, selecting the text in the image using Apple’s OCR and copying it into the app, or by drawing the kanji directly into the app.</em></p>

<p>It turns out these are two separate words (&ldquo;newly&rdquo; and &ldquo;information&rdquo;), but when used together as a compound, they mean something like “what’s new.” It’s commonly used on news websites and in apps.</p>

<p>Then, I create an Anki card that includes the sentence, target word, and additional details like audio for both the sentence and the word. While it&rsquo;s possible to do this directly in Anki, I’ve found that <a href="https://migaku.com/">Migaku’s</a> card creator works great—it automatically generates the audio files.</p>

<p><img src="./img/2025_07_10_migaku.png" alt="img_migaku" /></p>

<p>With a click of a button, the card is created and sent to Anki, where it becomes part of my learning routine.</p>

<p><img src="./img/2025_07_10_ankicard.png" alt="img_migaku" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a>, <a href='tag_sentence-mining.html'>sentence-mining</a></p>






























<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/sentence-mining-spam-messages.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./sentence-mining-spam-messages.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 13:47:36 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Learning conversational Japanese for (Coffee)bar
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Continuing to learn conversational words and phrases for my morning coffee. Here&rsquo;s today&rsquo;s video I used.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-top: 2rem;">
  <iframe 
    style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" 
    src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DXzLFk_uEr4?si=MZJfSre3SyP2WelK" 
    title="YouTube video player" 
    frameborder="0" 
    allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" 
    referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" 
    allowfullscreen>
  </iframe>
</div>


<p>Key takeaways:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>ホットかアイス、どちら<strong>になさいますか？</strong><br>Would you like it hot or iced?<br><strong>〜になさいますか？</strong> = respectful way to ask &ldquo;What will you choose?&rdquo; / &ldquo;What will you have?&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>お会計、500円<strong>で御座います</strong>。<br>That&rsquo;ll be 500 yen.<br><strong>で御座います</strong>: be, is</p></li>
<li>いえ、<strong>持ち帰り</strong>でお願いします。<br>No, I&rsquo;ll take it to go.<br><strong>持ち帰り (もちかえり)</strong>: takeout (i.e. food), take-out, takeaway, take-away</li>
<li>いらっしゃいませ、<strong>店内</strong>ご利用ですか？<br>Welcome, will you be dining in?<br><strong>店内 (てんない)</strong>: inside of a shop</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/japanese-at-coffee-bar.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./japanese-at-coffee-bar.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 11:11:59 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Picking up my first manga for immersion
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="./img/ws_slam_dunk_double.jpg" alt="slam_dunk_manga" /></p>

<p>write about atashi and nano particle.</p>

<p>New words learned today:</p>

<ul>
<li>ねじ - screw</li>
<li>クランプ - clamp</li>
<li>窓側 - window-side</li>
<li>引き上げる - pull up, salvage</li>
<li>値上がり - price rise</li>
<li>値上げ - price hike/raise</li>
<li>取り上げる - take up, confiscate</li>
<li>座席 - seat</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>





<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/pickig-up-my-first-manga-for-immersion.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./pickig-up-my-first-manga-for-immersion.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 11:22:17 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Coffee Confusion at Tully&rsquo;s
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="./img/ws_tully_kohi.jpg" alt="tully_coffee_sign" /></p>

<p>This morning, I decided to get regular coffee instead of my usual café latte at Tully’s. I was already a bit thrown off to learn that what they call “drip coffee” is just regular coffee that comes out of a machine—not hand-poured or anything fancy. But what really confused me was the Japanese menu, where “drip coffee” was labeled as 日本のコーヒー, which literally means “Japanese coffee.”</p>

<p>Not sure how to order, I tried saying “drippu kōhī” (ドリップコーヒー), and that worked just fine.</p>

<p>Out of curiosity, I looked up where this “Japanese coffee” label might come. Even ChatGPT doesn’t seem entirely sure why drip coffee was labeled that way in this case.</p>

<p><img src="./img/ws_chatgpt_dripcoffee.png" alt="chatgpt_explanation" /></p>

<p><strong>! UPDATE</strong></p>

<p>As I was talking about this with my wife later today, she pointed out that the kanji 本日 in this case is read as honjitsu, meaning “today.” So 本日のコーヒー means “today’s coffee,” referring to the specific beans being used that day.</p>

<p>Since 本日 can also be read as Nihon (“Japan”), I had initially interpreted it as “Japanese coffee,” but honjitsu makes much more sense in this context. That said, it would still feel a bit odd to order “today’s coffee,” so you’d probably just say “hot coffee” or “drippu kōhī” (ドリップコーヒー) when ordering.</p>

<p><img src="./img/ws_drippu.png" alt="anki_drip_coffee_card" />
<em>via: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZ16eqDVk3c&amp;t=45s</em></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a>, <a href='tag_vocabulary.html'>vocabulary</a>, <a href='tag_mining.html'>mining</a></p>






























<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/coffee-confusion.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./coffee-confusion.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 10:34:25 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Sentence Mining Within the Core 6K Deck
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I’ve worked through about two-thirds of the <a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1880390099">Core 6k Anki deck</a> so far. At some point, I got bored with it and shifted to sentence mining—mainly picking out new words from content I actually enjoy, like shows, articles, or YouTube videos.</p>

<p>But every now and then, especially while reading the <a href="https://www3.nhk.or.jp/news/easy/">NHK Easy website</a>, I come across words that turn out to be from the unseen part of the Core 6k deck. Even though I haven’t officially studied those cards yet, I end up mining them naturally through immersion.</p>

<p>It’s a good reminder that sentence mining isn’t just for completely new words outside the deck. It can also overlap with words I would have eventually reached in Core6k—just in a way that feels much more alive and relevant.</p>

<p><img src="./img/ws_sentence_mine_nhk_wide_dk.png" alt="sentence_mine" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a>, <a href='tag_sentence-mining.html'>sentence-mining</a></p>






























<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/sentence-mining-within-the-core-6k-deck.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./sentence-mining-within-the-core-6k-deck.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 10:49:59 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Realizing I Need Grammar
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Not knowing much grammar is becoming a real problem—something I’ve been really noticing now that I’ve moved to Japan. I had hoped to pick it up naturally through immersion, but since I’ve spent most of my time reviewing and adding new vocabulary and kanji readings, I feel like I’m missing the glue that holds everything together. It’s frustrating that I can’t form meaningful sentences when talking to people I meet. Even though I know a large number of isolated words, I still struggle to put them together in a way that makes sense. Just the other day, I met the owner of the izakaya next door, and when he started asking me questions about just moving here, I broke out in a sweat—I couldn’t find a way to respond beyond a few awkward words and gestures. In a way, when it comes to actual communication, I don’t feel much more advanced than I was two years ago.</p>

<p><img src="./img/ws_slamdunk_grammar.jpg" alt="img" /><em>img: slam dunk</em></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>










































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/realizing-i-need-grammar.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./realizing-i-need-grammar.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 11:13:47 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Japanese with Tanaka-san and Creating New Flashcards for Familiar Vocabulary
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="./img/tanaka-san-japanese.png" alt="img" /></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been sentence mining some new vocabulary words today from the beginner-friendly YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@japanese_tanakasan">Learn Japanese with Tanaka san</a> and wanted to share it here as I think it&rsquo;s a good channel. Right now I have about 80-90% word comprehension on most videos, which works well since I understand most of what is being said but am still picking up some new, high-frequency words.</p>

<p>What I&rsquo;ve found useful is that I&rsquo;m also encountering words I already know from my Anki deck, but seeing them used in natural contexts and different sentence patterns. It&rsquo;s been helpful for reinforcing my understanding and picking up more nuanced usage that I might have missed when just learning the isolated vocabulary. It&rsquo;s one thing to know a word&rsquo;s definition, but seeing how it actually works in conversation makes a difference.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been creating new flashcards for these already known words with the sentences from the videos, and now I&rsquo;m wondering if I should delete the original cards from my core 6k deck since the new context-based ones seem more useful.</p>

<p><img src="./img/tanaka-san-japanese2.png" alt="img" /><em>One of the cards I made today</em></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>










































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/learn-japanese-with-tanaka-san.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./learn-japanese-with-tanaka-san.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 19:42:30 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Learning 6K Vocabulary in a better context
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>One discrepancy with my Japanese studies at the moment is that I have spent the last two years learning around 4,500 vocabulary words that I can read, yet can&rsquo;t hold a basic conversation in Japanese. Although this was a conscious decision when studying, focusing more on understanding and reading instead of producing sentences, I feel somewhat worried about not being able to hold even very basic conversations, and I will be moving to Japan in two weeks.</p>

<p>Today I spent some time looking up basic conversations in Japanese and found this very helpful YouTube channel with great content.</p>

<p><img src="./img/juncho_01.png" alt="juncho_1" /></p>

<p><img src="./img/juncho_02.png" alt="juncho_1" />
This gives me more context. especially conbined with the previous card i created, to which this one is an answer</p>

<p><img src="./img/juncho_03.png" alt="juncho_1" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_japanese.html'>japanese</a></p>







<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/some-doubts-about-the-core6k-deck.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./some-doubts-about-the-core6k-deck.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 12:06:42 +0900</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Deciding on a Niche
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The rest of the text file is a <strong>Markdown</strong> blog post. The process will continue
as soon as you exit your editor.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blender.html'>blender</a>, <a href='tag_art.html'>art</a></p>





<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/deciding-on-a-niche.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./deciding-on-a-niche.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 17:51:48 +0900</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
