<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Wabisebi</title><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Blogging experiment. Japanese culture, language learning, coding and other things I'm into.</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:29:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 23:29:41 +0100</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Clean Slate
</title><description><![CDATA[

<h1>Clean Slate</h1>

<p>In 2001, I coded my first website, all about Spider-Man comics. I built it in HTML, complete with iframes and speech bubble drawings for the navigation. More sites followed: a Harry Potter fan site and a site celebrating the newly-launched Xbox to name a few.</p>

<p>Each project was abandoned as quickly as it was conceived. Once the novelty wore off, I&rsquo;d jump to the next thing, leaving behind a wasteland of iframes and half-written introductions.</p>

<p>This pattern of jumping from project to project has followed me throughout my life.</p>

<p>Two years ago, I started working on <em>Wabisebi</em>, a blog about Japan. Soon came additional ideas: book reviews, artist spotlights, and a language study section. I hired developers, kept adding features, and talked up this great project I was building. But like always, the novelty wore off and perfectionism kicked in. The thought of filling and illustrating the entire blog became overwhelming.</p>

<p>Recently I spent a lot of time reflecting on this recurring problem and decided to try out a change. Sometimes it&rsquo;s good to do the <em>reverse</em> of what has not been working. So, instead of building a website with tons of features that I then need to fill up, I&rsquo;ve decided to start bottom-up. Starting at its most basic fundamentals and only implementing things when they are <em>really</em> needed. I implemented a simple <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">bashlog script</a>, which converts markdown text into HTML pages and let&rsquo;s me post straight from the command line. Sometimes the best way forward is to strip everything back to its essentials and just begin.</p>

<p><img src="./img/pico-markdown.png" alt="cleanslate" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_life.html'>life</a>, <a href='tag_code.html'>code</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/clean-slate.html</link>
<guid>https://wabisebi.github.io/blog/./clean-slate.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Seb</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 12:41:52 +0100</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
